So I've been seeing a lot of footage this morning, not footage, but videos this morning
of folks in Chicago saying, stop saying they're coming for black folks in Chicago, saying that
people are trying to get clicks and that folks are using Chicago to get attention.
Y'all got it.
And the frustrations for me is that we cannot have multiple things be true at one time.
And I don't know why that is such a difficult thing, since as black people, we are the personification
of multiple things being true at all times.
But like, y'all got it.
I mean, I don't, I just, I'm, I'm seeing many black people.
I've seen at least five and that's many.
That's enough for me.
I've seen five black folks on this app saying, you know, don't talk about Chicago.
Um, don't talk about black people in Chicago.
Y'all trying to scare us.
Um, I don't know.
You know, what's interesting about this though, is that, so when Dr. Martin Luther King, right
before he was assassinated, he had went to Chicago, he had went to Chicago and, um, he went to Chicago
to work with the people because there was, um, what's it called?
Because there was a, you know, slumlords doing what they do.
And he was ran out of Chicago.
He was ran out of Chicago because the, uh, pastors in Chicago were like, don't come up here.
We got this.
We don't need you.
Um, and he was like, oh, all right.
And he left.
Now I know some of y'all are saying these are black Republican trolls and they're not because
in the same breath that there are black Chicago and saying, stop trying to scare black, black
people in Chicago.
Um, they're saying in the same breath that, you know, they don't, they don't F with Trump.
Like you're trying to scare us into coming outside.
Y'all should know that they're trying to incite violence with black Chicagoans.
That is true.
That, that doesn't change a reality that ICE is also harming black citizens in Chicago.
Like two things can be true at the same time.
You can simultaneously say these people are coming after black people in Chicago while
also saying, and so we have to really try our best to not give them what they're looking
for while still protecting our communities.
I don't know how that is, why that is so, um, difficult.
And so you have, so you'll have people here who are like, I'm in Chicago and it's not happening.
And then you have other people who are like, I'm in Chicago and it is happening.
Like you saw the people that were in the building.
You saw them talking about their experience and in your minds, anyone who's against this
or who doesn't think this is a big deal says, is saying that essentially, if they didn't
get taken, it's not that deep.
That's what you're saying.
If they didn't get taken, it's not that deep.
I saw folks saying y'all move these immigrants in here.
Okay, I'm going to walk us through this because I feel like folks don't, don't really grasp
the depth of these people's strategy.
When they were moving immigrants into black neighborhoods, when they were giving immigrants,
you know, uh, like food cards and calling cards, et cetera.
Yeah, that was a Trojan horse.
They were bringing them into these spaces that are predominantly black spaces for two reasons.
One, to sow seeds of divisiveness.
This is a classic.
I mean, this is basic, basic divide and conquer.
Bring people in, give them something that we're not giving you.
That's, I mean, that has literally been carried out over and over and over and over and over
and over and over.
Like that is absolutely something that we have seen before.
So the fact that we are acting like we don't recognize what it is when it's coming from
the same people who do this is like bonkers to me.
Second, the Trojan horse was also to put people in your neighborhoods for the purpose of inciting
violence.
So these things are true, right?
In, in a myriad of ways.
It's not just one thing at one time.
We have to have multiple capabilities of understanding.
And that is what critical thinking is.
And critical thinking, I want to explain, is not about a level of intellect.
It's a skill.
Critical thinking is a skill.
Like anything else, you can get better at it.
You might have an innate ability at it, but like learning how to put up drywall or learning
how to fix a mechanic.
I mean, sorry, learning how to fix an engine.
It's a skill.
It's an ability that you, it's, it's a way of reading, right?
So we as a nation have had that skill undermined in our education spaces.
So many people are able to like read, but they're not able to read with, with, um, they're not
able to read with critical thinking skills.
That being said, I have really good critical thinking skills.
I was really lucky to have that be like a very, very, very important aspect of my education.
And when I'm looking at certain things, my critical thinking skills get applied very quickly.
And I'm like, oh, I see what this is.
And what it is, is being able to draw from other pieces of information that, you know,
do, do critical, bringing those things together, doing comparative analysis.
Like, is this like this?
Right.
Also being able to look at what's said and what's not said, what's here and what's not here.
Like, these are the types of things that are imperative to being able to understand a media
that is really dedicated to you, um, not understanding.
Right.
So when we talk about Chicago, to me, it's like, well, at one, on one hand, yes, we do have
the very obvious desire to get black people to turn up so that there can be martial law.
Right.
We know that that is an absolute real effort that is being made as well as the uptick of
violence against black people in order to make that effort happen.
So to, to suggest that that's not happening is just simply disingenuous.
Like that's just disingenuous to suggest that that's not happening is disingenuous.
When you see, and it's happening in multiple ways, right?
It's not just like a, a, a, a violence in a physical way.
It's also emotional and mental way.
Right.
Like when you see, um, when you see like these white folks that have been, um, activated to
head out and go into predominantly black spaces to agitate, right?
Like that's not by accident.
They are in their spaces doing what we're doing right now, but for a whole other different
effort.
Okay.
They are activating each other.
And when I see people say things like they are not after generational black Americans,
I, I really think that you are a bot.
You must be a bot.
You're either a bot or you're an idiot or you're a black bot.
So you're a blot because that's just stupid.
So when we are seeing folks going into college camp, uh, HBCU campuses, I saw a white girl
at, um, I saw a white girl at a black joy festival asking folks, what do they think about Donald
Trump?
Um, um, I, I saw, uh, white boys in front of a black church in Philly, like this is not
by accident.
Um, with my mindset, what should the Chicago protocol be the same that it should be everywhere,
which is boning up your community and your community efforts, and also pressing the people
who supposedly have power, but also empowering each other.
But this, this idea that it's not happening and, and, and being angry at people for suggesting
or being angry at people on the internet for amplifying to me is counterproductive.
I find that to be counterproductive.
I don't know why that would be, um, helpful and scolding folks, um, who are paying attention
to this and who are saying, listen, this is not, this is not okay.
Like, let's be out here.
Um, that's, that to me is counterproductive.
Do I think it will affect the Chicago marathon this week?
I can think of at least 25 things that I care of more than that.
I don't know who the hell Demi Demure is.
Y'all keep responding to them.
But, um, hey Nana, but what are my thoughts on the No Kings protests?
I think No Kings protests are bullshit.
I think they are, or they are, um, what's the word I'm looking for?
They are controlled opposition.
It's a performance.
What's my take on the United States' role in Gaza?
Girl, just watch all my videos for that.
Y'all ask me two years after October 7th.
Like, what my thoughts are on the U.S.'s role in Gaza is, like, bizarre.
Hell no, I'm not going on no breakfast club anytime soon.
Y'all know I don't fuck with Charlemagne.
You think I should come to Chicago and see before watching videos and reading comments?
No, I don't need to come to Chicago to be in the effort of amplifying what is going on in the United States.
This idea that you all have that people need to physically travel to a place to be able to say,
hey guys, let's, let's put all eyes on that place is, like, weird to me.
Like, I don't need to come to Chicago to be in support of Chicago.
I don't need to come to specific places to be in support of specific places.
Like, what, why, why is this a thought process?
And you're asking me to come to Chicago, but you're not asking former president, former Chicago, uh, senator,
former Chicago organizer Barack Obama to come to Chicago.
So, like, that's the part for me that'd be blowing my whole head.
Like, what, what are y'all talking about?
And yes, we can watch a video and say, hey, that's not okay.
Yes, we can see that.
Like, we don't need to physically come to Chicago to see that.
Like, that's weird.
That's weird.
And it's also weird to think that what you think is happening in Chicago is the only thing that's happening in Chicago.
That's a weird concept.
Your individual experience cannot speak for everybody else's experience.
Like, that's just bizarre.
Well, they're not, no, because I'm not talking about media.
I'm not referencing things shown on CNN.
Like, don't come in, don't insult me like that.
Coming in here talking about, please recap, I just got here.
Catch up!
Thank you, show up to shine out, showed up and shined out.
Yes.
Can someone in the chat catch me up on the discussion?
Thank you.
They get it.
Um, yeah, like, no one here, it's like, I need y'all to actually follow my page.
Like, I actually am shadow banned.
So you either need to follow my page.
My show, Views for Amanda Land, is every Wednesday, 10 a.m. Eastern.
Um, Views for Amanda Land, 10 a.m. Eastern.
Wednesday, 10 a.m. Eastern on YouTube.
I do, I mean, like, the amount of, of content that I do is, is, like, weird for folks to be, like, confused.
So, um, you know, there is absolutely, uh, an intention that was stated.
This is not something that people are inferring.
There was an intention that was stated by Donald Trump and his administration to go into blue cities, states that have, um, states that have, uh, Democratic governors.
And to incite violence via ICE.
This is not something that people just kind of, like, piece together.
This was very directly stated.
Chicago was one of those cities.
So was D.C.
So was Portland.
So, to suggest that that is not the intention and that that's not the goal is, is weird to me.
To ever suggest, to ever suggest that black people are not a target by the government is weird.
That's weird.
Like, in, that's weird, bro.
There's just nothing to indicate otherwise.
So to all of a sudden have the most overtly white supremacist government that we've seen in maybe 60 years be in position and then have folks be like, yeah, but they're not coming for us.
Like, that's, because that's dumb as hell.
That's dumb.
So I'm not sure what that's about.
Um, and I always block people who ask what's the solution, because that is a bot.
Um, your mayor is not black.
He's Haitian.
Yo.
You know, folks who say shit like that, you deserve whatever's coming for you.
I, I want you to know that you deserve whatever's coming for you.
You really do.
You deserve whatever's coming for you.
Like, did you know that, that George Bush and the Clintons own land in Haiti?
They own land in Haiti that Haitians can't, can't go on.
It's in Cap Haitian, in Labadee.
They own land that is for cruise ships only in Haiti.
Did you know that there is a, there was a trade agreement BS that made it so that Haitians couldn't sell their own rice to each, to themselves.
They had to sell United States rice.
But the United States rice is toxic.
So, the United States rice that Haitians were forced to eat was making them sick.
Even though they had rice in their own country, they weren't allowed to sell it in their own country.
They had to buy rice from the United States.
That ended up also being toxic.
Okay?
Did you know that before, during the Civil War, they was trying to figure out where we're going to put these Negroes?
Right?
Because we, we, I mean, we may end this slavery thing.
And if we end this slavery thing, where are we going to put these niggas?
And so, one of the attempts was to put them in Haiti.
So, there was a coast of Haiti, where, or was it, it's an island or a coast off of Haiti, where literally black people who were freed slaves were sent.
And there was a white man there who had been put in charge of making sure everyone gets settled.
And he had told President Lincoln, listen, I got everything set up, everything's going to be cool, everything's going to be sweet, you know, everybody's going to live really well.
Mind you, remember, Haiti has Haitians.
Then, they find out, actually, no, that's not what's going on.
People are there dying because there is no real place to eat, there's no real food to eat, there's no real living quarters, the bugs are killing them.
And this white man was lying and got paid a bunch of bread to have them come down there.
Huh.
Funny.
Because something very similar is happening in Puerto Rico.
Where in Puerto Rico, mad people don't have electricity, but you have all of these American contractors who are getting paid to, quote, unquote, fix the grid while not doing anything.
So, this is a common practice of using these nations that are adjacent to the United States to make rich white people, to make rich people, white people in the United States richer.
And then people like you come and say things like, well, if they're Haitian, they're not American.
And I think that it's really important to understand that, one, people are individuals, so there's different relationships that people have to their heritage and to their American experience than others.
And, two, in the case of Haiti, and specifically Haiti, listen, the amount of thievery that the United States has done, the amount of destabilization that the United States have done to Haiti.
Like, Jeffrey Sachs talks about this.
Economist and professor Jeffrey Sachs talks about how Papa Doc was like, yo, is it Papa Doc?
No, it's not Papa Doc, but he talks about one of the Haitian dictators, not dictators, actually, one of the Democratic elected Haitian presidents had told him, like, yo, I think they're going to murk me.
I think the CIA is going to murk me.
And he was like, no, come on, they're not going to murk you.
And he was like, no, I really think they are.
They're trying to kill me.
And, you know, Dr. Sachs, in his heart of hearts, like, no, America's not that bad, was like, no, like, they got you.
You're going to be good.
Then he came back to the States, and what happened?
Pop, pop, murk.
Murk.
Did you know that they brought in Haitian soldiers?
They brought in brothers from Haiti to fight in the Revolutionary War.
Did you know that?
Thank you to everybody who's buying a badge, since this is free game.
So, you know, I know that for a lot of y'all history, like, doesn't matter to you.
You just saying whatever.
But it does matter.
It does matter.
You know?
History does matter.
It does matter.
So, it matters if for any reason, because you're trying to construct a future.
And like the fat man said right here, like, you can't really do that without context.
So, yeah.
That's where we are, y'all.
So, I'll see you tomorrow morning on Views for Amanda Land at 10 a.m.
And let's see, who are our guests tomorrow on Views for Amanda Land?
Our guests tomorrow on Views for Amanda Land are Davidson Boswell.
No.
Yes.
Davidson Boswell and Joy Malonza.
Wow.
So, that's what's going on tomorrow on Views for Amanda Land.
So, come and rock with us.
I just want y'all to...
I just want folks to...
I don't know.
Anyway, Chicago, y'all got it.
You on here, Chicago, come out my mouth one more time.
Y'all got it.
Okay?
We'll leave you right the F alone.
I don't need to be yelled at more than once.
Y'all got it.